[intriguing music playing]
[indistinct background chatter, laughter]
BALLAD OF THE HAPPY DESTRUCTION
[Saji] Another perk of our new recruits,
we're finally able to distribute
some free meals.
We don't even have to sell Black Powder.
We have more than enough support
from the wealth of this mansion.
The boss still hasn't come back yet, huh?
No, but it seems
Ton and Natsuki have come back.
They've called a meeting,
'cause apparently,
they've got something to show us.
[growling softly]
[flesh wobbling]
- [grunts]
- [intriguing music playing]
[both gasp]
Amazing. There's not a scratch on her!
That's defense Magic for you.
We may have lost Kikurage
to the En family,
but when she was injured
during the battle,
Natsuki's Magic was awakened.
This thing is like a protective suit.
It may even be able to repel Magic.
[Ton] Yeah! Let's try it next time!
Hang on.
So, if Natsuki can use
Magic as amazing as this,
then, there's no need for her
to stay with the Cross-Eyes.
She can make a good living
with this power, you know?
[Ton] Now that you mention it,
you have a point.
[all gasp]
[Natsuki chuckling]
[Saji] Natsuki, your left eye!
After we returned to the mansion
and healed my arm,
I got this eye tattooed as well.
Listen, guys,
even if I can use Magic now,
I'll always be a member of the Cross-Eyes!
Natsuki...
Yeah, that's just the way I feel about it.
What do you say?
I stay here in the mansion?
Yes, of course you can!
After all, if things get bad,
we might need you around to protect us!
You... you mean it? Oh!
[gasps]
Starting today,
you're a full-fledged member
of the Cross-Eyes.
[gasps] Thanks, Saji.
Thanks, everyone. I won't let you down.
[frantic electronic music playing]
[lyrics in Japanese]
THE BEGINNING
[music fades]
[Nikaido] This is crazy.
I never thought I'd come back
to this mansion, let alone as a man.
[Kawajiri] I gotta say,
you're pretty handsome like this, Nikaido.
[Nikaido chuckles]
You look like
a completely different person.
By the way,
these clothes are really heavy.
[Kawajiri] I used Magic
to make 'em that way.
Your training is still ongoing.
Also, the Magic that powers this disguise
only lasts four hours.
After that, you're gonna return
to your original form, so be careful.
Understood. Four hours...
So, around nine o'clock.
[Kawajiri] A fellow devil once told me
something that could help us.
Apparently, somewhere in this mansion,
there's a room filled solely
with the gifts En received from devils.
Does that ring any bells?
[Nikaido] Mm.
Now that you mention it,
this one time,
En took me to a strange room
and made me listen
to him brag about how cool it was.
Maybe that's the room
you're talking about.
If I remember correctly,
some kind of object
served as a hidden door.
[Kawajiri] Hmm...
All right, let's go look for it.
[intriguing music fades]
Was this room also used
by an En Family officer?
Yeah, this was Noi's room.
Look for anything of monetary value.
Enough with the money already.
So we're looking for information, right?
A clue to where the surviving
En family members might be hiding?
- Hmm...
- [Ton] There sure are a lot of photos.
When the boss gets back,
let's take a group photo together!
Yeah!
I can't wait to put it up here!
[giggles]
[uneasy music playing]
[flies buzzing]
[Risu] Well, well, well,
if it isn't the Cross-Eyes B-squad.
- It's been a while.
- [gasps]
Ri... Risu?!
It's a good thing I held off
erasing these damn tattoos off my face.
I got in here easily.
Now, maybe you've had enough time
to jog your memories.
Risu, it's like I told you before,
none of us have any idea who murdered you.
[Risu] Hmm...
Yeah? Then maybe your beloved Dokuga
is hiding a few things from you guys.
[all gasping]
[Risu] Because he seemed to know
a lot about me.
No worries,
I'll have to ask Dokuga about it myself.
Over our dead bodies, you freak!
[Risu, demonically] Oh yeah?
Just try to stop me, you bastards!
[growling]
[Curse] There it is.
I can feel it...
your murderous intent!
[music stops]
[Aikawa grunts]
Just as I thought,
no guards at this entrance.
[chuckling]
That part-time job for Tanba
paid off after all.
All right, time to find Risu.
[gentle gurgling]
[Tetsujo] Dokuga,
what are you going to do about Natsuki?
If we don't act,
she could be killed, just like Risu was.
[Aikawa] Natsuki might get killed?
What are they talking about?
[pensive music playing]
I mean, how long until
the boss decides he wants her magic?
[Aikawa] Natsuki has Magic?
You're not just gonna sit back
and watch him take it, are you?
We have to stop him!
We need to figure out some way--
I'm thinking about
giving Natsuki a mission.
Something to keep her far away from here.
I'll talk to the boss while she's gone.
I'll ask him
not to kill any more companions.
Tetsujo...
I'm trying so hard.
I want to believe in the boss again.
Dokuga...
No one cared about
some worthless humans like us except him.
When our only option was
to lay down and die,
he gave us a path to keep living.
Hey... You're right, Dokuga.
Let's trust the boss.
I'm sure he'll do the right thing.
[Aikawa] Hmm...
[Nikaido] This whole area
was En's private space.
This is where my bedroom was.
Kikurage's too.
[Kawajiri] I see.
Maybe the room
we're looking for is nearby.
- Who are these guys?
- [tense music playing]
This area is off-limits to non-officers.
Let me handle this.
[Nikaido] Hmm...
I feel like I'm remembering something.
- [Tetsujo] You two.
- [both gasp]
Show me your arms!
I need to check your smoke.
I have a feeling these guys
don't want us poking around here.
I bet they're Cross-Eyes officers.
What do we do?
Come on, hurry up and show me your arms!
[Kawajiri] Use this
as a training opportunity.
You deal with him.
I'll keep searching for the book.
[gasps] Where'd she go? Oh!
[dramatic music playing]
[yelps]
[both grunting]
[Nikaido] Take that!
[Tetsujo grunting]
[Nikaido] My clothes are still heavy!
[grunting]
[Tetsujo] I've got you now!
[Nikaido grunts]
[both straining]
- [Nikaido grunting]
- Oof!
[Tetsujo splutters]
- [music fades]
- [Nikaido sighs]
[groans] Sorry, Dokuga...
Tetsujo, you did well.
Now, you.
- [chuckling]
- [Dokuga] Who are you?
[tense music playing]
[Aikawa] Why are Cross-Eyes
fighting each other?
- [Dokuga grunts]
- [gasps]
He's fast!
Screw training,
this thing is gonna get me killed!
[dramatic music playing]
[seething breath, growls]
[Nikaido grunting]
[pained grunting]
[groans softly]
[pained grunt]
[Nikaido] Ugh!
[Dokuga screaming]
Dokuga! [grunts]
- Huh?
- [Tetsujo grunting]
- [Nikaido grunting]
- [grunts, yelps]
Hmph.
[Tetsujo] Damn it! You bastard!
- You're getting...
-...too cocky!
Huh? Uh...
- [grunts]
I can't waste all day fighting these guys.
Here's my chance.
- [gasps] Oof!
- [Nikaido grunts]
That hurts...
Ah! You!
[Aikawa] That hurts...
- [strong wind blowing]
- [thunder rumbling]
[Vaux] Hmm...
What the hell
have you been working on over there?
It's Caiman's medical record.
Looking it over,
you can clearly see that deep down,
Caiman is human.
But there's a little abnormality
that's caught my attention.
Well, Caiman is a victim of Magic.
It's only natural there'd be
a few things that are out of place.
That's not what I'm talking about.
How should I put it?
[sighs]
I wish I could talk this over
with Mr. Kasukabe.
If I'm right about this,
we may have found the reason
why Caiman's head regenerates.
I can't believe it's already been
a whole month since then.
I wonder what happened
to Caiman and Nikaido.
QUESTION & ANSWER
[heavy breathing]
He must've come this way to escape.
Damn it! Looks like we lost him.
I hate big houses.
More importantly, Dokuga, are you okay?
[unsteadily] Yeah...
I bet he's at the connecting passage.
Let's go!
All right, it looks like
we managed to shake them off.
- Who the hell are you?
- Huh?
Why do I have to hide together
with a damn Cross-Eye?
[Nikaido grunts]
Come on, you're gonna be in
as much trouble as me
if they find you here.
[gasps] That's it. I remember now!
- It's this stone statue!
- Huh?
Huh, En really thought this through.
He knew no one would wanna
mess with a devil statue.
If I remember correctly...
[Aikawa] Are you sure it's okay
to treat a devil statue like that?
Oh!
Oh wow...
I found it!
The entrance to En's treasure room!
You get in too.
Hide in there until things cool down.
What?! Why do I have to?!
- I'm busy. Whoa!
- Just get... in... the room!
[Aikawa yelping, screaming]
[grunts]
[gasps]
Huh?
What the hell is this place?
This is a top-secret room that En filled
with his most cherished treasures.
Cherished treasures, eh?
Look like a bunch of junk to me.
Also, you haven't told me who you are.
You've been acting like you know me!
Oh! I thought you'd noticed by now.
It's me silly!
I'm Nikaido!
I used Magic to disguise myself
as a man to sneak in here.
What?!
You're telling me you're Nikaido?
You know, now that you mention it...
Just kidding,
I'm not falling for that bullshit. I...
- Ugh...
- Hey, uh, you're hurt pretty bad.
[sighs] Don't worry. It's nothing serious.
- All right, gotta find this book.
- Huh?!
Man, I'm hungry.
Oh, that's right.
I'll eat the curry bread that I brought.
TO EN, CHIDARUMA
A LUCKY DAY IN MARCH
I mean, even if you are Nikaido,
I only met you for the first time
the other day.
I don't even remember your face that well.
- [Nikaido] Oh!
- Hm?
Here it is. This has to be it!
[Aikawa] What's that?
You came all this way
just to steal a stupid book?
Yeah.
This book contains all the information
I need to master my powers...
- [clock bongs]
- [both] Hmm?
- Ah! Oh crap! It's nine o'clock!
- Hmm?
[gulping]
See... I told you
[gulps]
[gasps] Nikaido...
Caiman...
[Aikawa] I told you a million times,
I'm not this "Caiman" guy
you keep talking about.
Jeez, you're annoying!
I guess I did name you Caiman
without much thought about it.
But still... you're telling me
when you transformed back,
you forgot about me, the Hole, the gyoza?
[gasps] Gyoza...
Stop it!
I don't know anything about gyoza!
[man 1] I heard the officers
are fighting a monster in this wing!
- [man 2] Hurry.
- [man 1] Let's take a look!
What's going on?
[indistinct background chatter]
[Saji] Everyone, back off!
It's dangerous! Get back!
Damn it. How pathetic.
[Ton] We can't attack Curse from our side.
We need to think of something
to chase him away.
- Maybe we have to let him talk to Dokuga.
- [Natsuki] Wait, please!
I'll use my Magic to deal with him!
Please, everyone, stay back!
[Saji] Natsuki!
Oh!
That's Natsuki.
What's that black thing over there?
[Aikawa gasps]
- [straining]
- Don't be reckless.
Natsuki,
that cursed bastard never gives up!
[gasps] Wait.
I can't believe it.
Since when can she use Magic?
[Aikawa groans]
[suspenseful music building]
[Aikawa groaning]
[snarls]
[wobbling]
If it comes down to it,
we are not going to let her die.
[Curse] I feel it... I can feel it...
Your murderous intent!
[roars]
[snarling]
[dramatic music playing]
[muffled grunting]
[Curse gasps]
[pained grunting]
Risu!
[Natsuki grunts]
[Curse gasps, snarls]
[seethes]
[Natsuki grunts]
[grunts, splutters]
- [grunts]
- [Curse growling]
[Aikawa] Hmm.
- [whispering] Hey, Nikaido!
- Oh, Asu!
So there you are.
I've caught him!
- All right, way to go, Natsuki!
- You're amazing!
- [Natsuki] What should we do?
- We're gonna hang him outside!
[Curse snarls]
- [Aikawa] Uh...
- Oh! Hey?!
Wait, that guy...
What's wrong? What's all this commotion?
Dokuga!
Risu turned into Curse
and attacked us again!
What?!
It's okay.
Natsuki was able to
take him straight down!
We found out that her Magic
can totally defend against curses!
[Natsuki giggling]
[both gasping]
- [Dokuga] Natsuki, come with us.
- Huh?!
Wait. Why?
[tense music building]
Risu!
Hey! Risu!
[music fades]
[Aikawa straining]
- Oh!
- Risu, get a hold of yourself!
- Wait. Risu was that monster from earlier?
- Hey, Risu!
[whispers] Nikaido, we've got the book.
Time to get out of here.
Oh, right.
[gasps] Hey, aren't you...
It's Kawajiri. Been a while, Aikawa.
[gasps]
[Nikaido] Aikawa,
let's get out of here together.
[Aikawa grunts]
Sorry, but I can't.
Go on without me. [whimpers]
Please, take care of him.
He's my partner.
So, Risu is your partner?
Now I understand.
Got it. Leave it to me.
But what are you going to do?
You've been hiding so many things from me
since the very beginning. What's going on?
- If you could only remember what we--
- [Aikawa groaning]
- [splutters, gasps]
- [Nikaido] Oh!
Oh...
- [Nikaido] What's wrong? Are you okay?
- Don't come near me!
[gasps]
- [Aikawa] Don't come near me!
- [uneasy music playing]
[Nikaido] I know it's your life,
and you can live it however you want,
just... you should come
eat some gyoza sometime.
I'll give you 20% off.
[Aikawa] I can't anymore...
I can't...
[groans] Oh!
Nikaido, let's go!
Oh, Caiman...
- [ominous music playing]
- [Aikawa breathing heavily]
I'm sick of it...
[groaning, retching]
My head!
Ah! I'm sick of it... [retching]
[coughing, retching]
[gasps]
[breathing shakily]
[music continues]
[gasping] I'm sick of it...
[gurgles, retching]
[uneasy music playing]
[Ai] Why fight it?
[labored breathing, gasping]
Shut up...
[Ai] When from the very start...
[spluttering]
[groaning]
[muffled grunting, groaning]
...you never existed.
[uneasy music continues]
[music intensifies]
[padding footsteps squelching]
[choked gagging]
[groaning]
[music fades]
[Natsuki squeals excitedly] Yay!
A mission, a mission!
I can't believe Dokuga is letting me
do a job all by myself.
[giggling happily]
Hmm... So it's a search
for an elite Sorcerer.
EN'S MANSION, DOG, CONVENIENCE STORE
FOREST, TARGET
It's pretty far away.
I wanted the boss to at least see my Magic
before I set out.
[tense music playing]
But they told to leave
through the back door
so no one would notice.
I wonder why?
[Natsuki gasps]
The boss!
I... I, uh... Oh?
Huh?
[squeals]
I... I'm about to start a mission!
Um, s... so I, uh...
When I get back, I want all the Cross-Eyes
to take a picture together--
Whoa!
I want you...
Oh, Boss...
- [kissing]
- [muffled grunt]
- [boss growling softly]
- [Natsuki whimpering]
[muffled wail]
[gasps]
[spluttering] B... Boss...
[weakly] W... why?
[ragged exhaling]
[ominous whirring]
[Japanese theme song playing]
THE END
[narrator] What we learned in Episode 23.
There was a major clue
in Caiman's medical record.
Aikawa entrusted Risu to Nikaido.
Natsuki wanted to take
a picture with everyone.
What we're going to learn in Episode 24,
it's still lost in chaos.
This is Dorohedoro!